Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Mary Fanton Roberts papers
1880-1956
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Roberts, Mary Fanton
3.8 linear feet
The papers of art writer and editor Mary Fanton Roberts measure 3.8 linear feet and are dated 1880 to 1956. The bulk of this collection is Roberts' correspondence with numerous important artists, dancers, actors, writers, and musicians of the day. Also found are scattered biographical materials, family correspondence, writings, printed material, photographs and artwork.
Provenance
The collection was donated in 1957 by Phoebe DuBois and Violet Organ.
Alternative Forms Available
The microfilm of this collection was digitized in 2007 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Restrictions on Access
The microfilm of this collection has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website. Use of material not microfilmed or digitized requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Mary Fanton Roberts was born in Brooklyn, New York in 1864. When she was a young girl her family moved to Deadwood, in the Montana territory, where her father had mining prospects. When she was old enough, she and her sister were sent back to New York to attend the Albany Female Academy. After finishing school, Roberts pursued journalism and became a staff writer for four years for the Herald Tribune, the Journal, and the Sun in New York. During her long career she was editor of Demorest Magazine, editor-in-chief of New Idea Woman's Magazine, managing editor of The Craftsman, and creator and editor of The Touchstone Magazine and Decorative Arts magazine. Her longest period at one publication was seventeen years as editor of Arts and Decoration. She often wrote articles on the topic of decorative arts and home decorating, and published two books, Inside 100 Homes, and 101 Ideas for Successful Interiors.
In 1906 she married William Carman Roberts, writer and editor of Literary Digest for thirty years. They lived in Manhattan and Waterford, Connecticut.
Roberts was very involved in the artistic, theatrical, and literary circles in New York City, and met and became friends with many young avant garde American artists, including Robert Henri and John Sloan. Through her husband she met many writers and poets, including Theodore Dreiser and Bliss Carman. Roberts was active in organizations such as the Women's City Club, Pen and Brush, and the MacDowell Society and also attended countless art openings, theater performances, and other social events. As an avid supporter of modern dance, she became friends with many performers, including Isadora Duncan and Angna Enters. After her husband's death in 1941, Roberts moved to the Chelsea Hotel, where she lived for the rest of her life. She maintained lifelong relationships with a wide circle of friends and continued to correspond with them and attend social events until her death in 1956 at the age of 92.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of art writer and editor Mary Fanton Roberts measure 3.8 linear feet and are dated 1880 to 1956. The collection is comprised mainly of correspondence with family members, artists, dancers, actors, writers, musicians, and visual and performing arts organizations. Also found are scattered biographical materials, writings, printed material, photographs and artwork.
The collection contains a small amount of biographical material about Mary Fanton Roberts and her husband, William Carman Roberts, including his journal of a vacation with Ernest Thompson Seton and his wife. Personal Correspondence is with her husband and sister Belle Fanton, and with friends. Business and political correspondence documents her career as a magazine editor and writer, her participation in political organizations and events, her participation in radio talks, and her correspondence regarding war issues.
Art correspondence/subject files include correspondence with and collected materials on artists, photographers, art patrons, critics, and wives of artists, as well as arts organizations, museums, and schools. Correspondence of note is with George Gray Barnard, Gutzon Borglum, Ben Ali Haggin, Leon Kroll, Frederic Remington, W. Goodridge Roberts, Nicholas Roerich, Pierre Troubetzkoy, illustrator Oliver Herford, John Butler Yeats, and Ashcan school artists Robert Henri, John Sloan, and William Glackens, as well as many others. Dance and theatre correspondence/subject files include correspondence with actors, dancers, playwrights, patrons, organizations and theatres. Correspondence of note in this series is with Charles "Orlando" Coburn, Eva Le Gallienne, Angna Enters, and the "Duncan Dancers." Literary and music orrespondence/subject files include correspondence with authors, poets, critics, singers, publishers, and musicians, such as Bliss Carman, Yvette Guilbert, and Lloyd Osbourne. Additional material found in these subject files, other than letters, includes invitations, photographs, calling cards, artwork, news clippings, and printed material.
Writings by Roberts include an autobiographical essay about her youth and early career, guest lists and notes concerning hosted events, and typescripts of poems by her niece Dorothy Gostwick Roberts. Printed material is comprised of art exhibition catalogs, published articles and trade bulletins written by Roberts, and newsclippings. Photographs are of Roberts, her family, friends, and places she lived, and include autographed portraits given to her, primarily from actors and actresses. Also found are photographs taken by Nickolas Muray of art models. Scattered artwork in this collection includes several small drawings by unidentified artists, as well as a pencil portrait of Roberts by John Butler Yeats.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Seton, Ernest Thompson, 1860-1946
Subjects-Topical:
Ashcan school of art; Editors -- New York (State) -- New York; Art critics -- New York (State) -- New York; Authors -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Works of art; Photographs
Names:
Roberts, William C.; Fanton, Belle; Barnard, George Grey, 1863-1938; Borglum, Gutzon, 1867-1941; Haggin, Ben Ali, 1882-1951; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974; Remington, Frederic, 1861-1909; Rerikh, Nikolai Konstantinovich, 1874-1947; Troubetzkoy, Pierre, 1864-1936; Herford, Oliver, 1863-1935; Yeats, John Butler, 1839-1922; Henri, Robert, 1865-1929; Sloan, John, 1871-1951; Glackens, William J., 1870-1938; Coburn, Charles Douville; Le Gallienne, Eva, 1899-; Enters, Angna, 1907-; Carman, Bliss, 1861-1929; Guilbert, Yvette, 1865-1944; Osbourne, Lloyd, 1868-1947; Muray, Nickolas, 1892-1965; Roberts, Goodridge, 1904-; Roberts, Dorothy, 1906-
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 11 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1906, 1912-1941, undated (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 2: Personal Correspondence, 1902-1951, undated (Box 1; 7 folders)
Series 3: Business and Political Correspondence, 1903-1959, undated (Box 1; 6 folders)
Series 4: Art Correspondence/Subject Files, 1898-1956, undated (Box 1-2; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 5: Dance and Theatre Correspondence/Subject Files, 1902-1953, undated (Box 2-3; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 6: Literary and Music Correspondence/Subject Files, 1900-1952, undated (Box 3; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 7: General Correspondence, 1898-1946, undated (Box 3-4; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Writings, 1915-1926, 1952, undated (Box 4; 3 folders)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1899, 1909-1947, undated (Box 4-5; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, 1880-circa 1943, undated (Box 5; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 11: Artwork, 1906, undated (Box 5; 3 folders)
For the most part, the arrangement of the papers established for initial microfilming has been maintained. Researchers will find it useful to browse all of the correspondence/subject files for relevant content as there is overlap between the Subject/Correspondence Files.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1912-1941, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1; 2 folders)
  This series contains biographical material about Mary Fanton Roberts, including the wedding announcement for her marriage to William Carman Roberts and a questionnaire and published entry about her career in Who's Who in the East. Also contained in this series is biographical material about William Carman Roberts, including a Naturalization Alien Registration Form, personal correspondence, notes, and a journal kept while he and Mary were on a trip to the Adirondacks with their friend Ernest Thompson Seton, founder of the Boy Scouts of America, and his wife Grace.
  - Mary Fanton Roberts Biographical Material, 1906, 1940-1941 (Reel D161, Frame 1-8)
  - William C. Roberts Biographical Material, 1912-1939, undated (Reel D161, Frame 254-335)
- Personal Correspondence, 1902-1951, undated, Series 2:; (Box 1; 7 folders)
  Personal correspondence includes letters between Mary Fanton Roberts and her husband "Billy" during periods of travel, and letters between Mary and her sister Belle Fanton. Also found is correspondence regarding Roberts' club activities, including P. E. N. (An International Association of Poets, Playwrights, Editors, Essayists and Novelists), the Drama Society, and various women's clubs. Miscellaneous personal correspondence includes letters and brief notes from friends and acquaintances, many expressing thanks, replying to her invitations to visit, and condolences on the death of her husband. This series also includes two valentines to Mary from her husband. Items are arranged chronologically within each folder.
  - Correspondence with William C. Roberts (1 of 2), 1904-1929, 1937-1940, undated (Reel D161, Frame 62-172)
  - Correspondence with William C. Roberts (2 of 2), 1904-1929, 1937-1940, undated (Reel D161, Frame 173-253)
  - Correspondence with Belle Fanton, 1902-1941, undated (Reel D161, Frame 336-356)
  - Club Activities, 1916-1941, undated (Reel D161, Frame 513-595)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence, A-H, 1903-1948, undated (Reel D161, Frame 357-410)
  - Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence, K-Z, 1902-1951, undated (Reel D161, Frame 411-460)
  - Valentine Cards, 1921, undated (Reel Box 1, Frame Folder 9)
- Business and Political Correspondence, 1903-1959, undated, Series 3:; (Box 1; 6 folders)
  This series contains correspondence related to Mary Fanton Roberts' work and political activities, including correspondence regarding her writing and editorial work. Correspondence related to her political activities includes numerous invitations to political and war-time events, as well as letters from political and civic organizations of which she was a member, including the Women's Committee of One Hundred for Non-Partisan City Government and the Academy of Political Science. This series also contains correspondence regarding Roberts' participation in several radio talks discussing home decoration and her professional editorial work.
  - Magazine Work Correspondence, 1903-1934 (Reel D161, Frame 637-663)
  - Miscellaneous Business Correspondence, 1903-1943, undated (Reel D161, Frame 461-487)
  - Political Correspondence, 1911-1927 (Reel D161, Frame 970-1000)
  - Political Correspondence, 1928-1948, undated (Reel D161, Frame 1001-1035)
  - Radio Broadcasts Correspondence, 1925-1926, 1936-1937, 1959 (Reel D162, Frame 1-14)
  - War Issues Correspondence, 1916-1918, 1941, 1944 (Reel D161, Frame 1036-1064)
- Art Correspondence/Subject Files, 1898-1956, undated, Series 4:; (Box 1-2; 0.8 linear feet)
  This series documents Mary Fanton Roberts' art-related activities and memberships, as well as friendships with painters, sculptors, photographers, art patrons, art critics, and wives of artists. Folders may contain a variety of material on the subject, including letters, invitations, photographs, artwork, programs, catalogs, news clippings, and other printed material. Topics included in the correspondence range from invitations to art events, thanks for publishing articles in her magazines, accounts of travels abroad, and other general news.
  Roberts was friends with many prominent artists from the early twentieth century and a small amount of their correspondence is found here, including Ashcan school artists Robert Henri, John Sloan, George Bellows, and William Glackens. Other correspondence of note is with sculptors George Gray Barnard, Gutzon Borglum, painters Ben Ali Haggin, Leon Kroll, W. Goodridge Roberts, Nicholas Roerich, and Pierre Troubetzkoy, as well as illustrator Oliver Herford. Much of the correspondence is also with the artists' wives. Additional significant correspondence is with Belle da Costa Greene, librarian for J. P. Morgan, and art writer Edward Alden Jewell. Items of note in this series include illustrated cards and letters from Edward Caswell, F. Luis Mora, and Ethel Myers, photographs of Frederic Remington and Bessie Potter Vonnoh, eleven small watercolor American Indian scenes by Edwin Deming, three etchings by John Sloan, and an essay by Gustav Stickley (located in The Craftsman folder). Within each folder, correspondence is arranged before other materials. Additional invitations to art related events can be found in series 7, General Correspondence.
  - Alexander, Elizabeth (Mrs. John W.), 1911-1941, undated (Reel D162, Frame 677-686)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1928-1945 (Reel D162, Frame 687-694)
  - American-Sweden News Exchange, 1930 (Reel D162, Frame 695-701)
  - Architectural League of New York, 1908-1917 (Reel D162, Frame 702-707)
  - Armory Show (International Exhibition of Modern Art), 1913 (Reel D162, Frame 708-712)
  - Associated American Artists, circa 1940 (Reel D162, Frame 713-723)
  - Barnard, George Gray & Edna, 1908-1938 (Reel D162, Frame 724-747)
  - Bellows, George, 1910-1951, undated (Reel D162, Frame 748-764)
  - Borglum, Gutzon & Mary, 1908-1914, undated (Reel D162, Frame 765-797)
  - Borglum, Emma Vignal (Mrs. Solon H.), 1909-1916, undated (Reel D162, Frame 798-803)
  - Bossom, Alfred & Emily, 1929, undated (Reel D162, Frame 804-805)
  - Bracken, Clio (Mrs. William B.), 1900, 1919-1921, undated (Reel D162, Frame 806-812)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1918-1944, undated (Reel D162, Frame 813-817)
  - Caffin, Charles, 1911 (Reel D162, Frame 818-819)
  - Calder, A. Stirling, 1917, 1927 (Reel D162, Frame 820-823)
  - Caparn, Harold & Rhys, 1937-1944, undated (Reel D162, Frame 824-830)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1908-1920 (Reel D162, Frame 831-834)
  - Caswell, Edward, 1956 (Reel D162, Frame 835)
  - Chambers, Robert W., Mary, & Elise, 1915-1916, undated (Reel D162, Frame 836-847)
  - Chanler, Robert W., 1927-1930 (Reel D162, Frame 848-849)
  - Connecticut College Library, 1945 (Reel D162, Frame 850-852)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1919, 1929, undated (Reel D162, Frame 853-854)
  - Cortissoz, Royal, 1942-1943 (Reel D162, Frame 855-857)
  - The Craftsman, 1915-1916, undated (Reel D162, Frame 858-867)
  - Cram, Ralph Adams, 1923 (Reel D162, Frame 868)
  - Crowninshield, Frank, 1922-1948 (Reel D162, Frame 869-879)
  - Davey, Randall, 1925-1930, undated (Reel D162, Frame 880-890)
  - De Casseres, Benjamin, 1929, undated (Reel D162, Frame 891-894)
  - Deming, Edwin W. & Therese O., 1910-1940, undated (Reel D162, Frame 895-912)
  - Dielman, Mr. & Mrs. Frederick, circa 1906 (Reel D162, Frame 913)
  - Dougherty, Paul, 1910-1919, 1940 (Reel D162, Frame 914-917)
  - French, Daniel Chester, 1917 (Reel D162, Frame 918-919)
  - Fromkes, Eva Maurice, 1933, undated (Reel D162, Frame 920-925)
  - Garden Club of America, 1928-1929, undated (Reel D162, Frame 926-939)
  - Genthe, Arnold, 1936, 1943, undated (Reel D162, Frame 940-947)
  - Gilbert, C. Allan, 1915 (Reel D162, Frame 948-951)
  - Glackens, William, Edith, and Ira, 1909-1947, undated (Reel D162, Frame 952-1043)
  - Greene, Belle da Costa, 1910-1916, 1948, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1042-1072)
  - Haggin, Ben Ali, Lee W., and Bonnie, 1909-1932, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1073-1125)
  - Hale, Gardner, 1922-1931, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1126-1133)
  - Hassam, Child, circa 1917 (Reel D162, Frame 1134)
  - Henri, Robert, 1908-1939, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1135-1205)
  - Herford, Oliver & Peggy, 1915-1947, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1206-1231)
  - Herter, Mr. & Mrs. Albert, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1232)
  - Higgins, Eugene, 1907-1930 (Reel D162, Frame 1233-1241)
  - Independent Artists Exhibition, 1910 (Reel D162, Frame 1242)
  - Jewell, Edward Alden, 1936-1945, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1243-1305)
  - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1916, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1306-1309)
  - Judd, Joseph A., 1934 (Reel D162, Frame 1310-1311)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1926-1944 (Reel D162, Frame 1312-1330)
  - Lamb, Charles R., 1908, 1910 (Reel D162, Frame 1331-1332)
  - Lane, John, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1333-1334)
  - Lavery, Sir John, circa 1924, 1930, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1335-1337)
  - Lawton, Mary, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1338-1340)
  - Levy, Florence, 1919 (Reel D162, Frame 1341)
  - Lie, Jonas, 1938, 1940 (Reel D162, Frame 1342-1349)
  - Low, Will H., 1916 (Reel D162, Frame 1355)
  - Lynch, George, 1924-1925, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1356-1361)
  - Lyons, Edward, 1946, 1947, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1362-1365)
  - MacDowell Club, NYC, 1910-1928, undated (Reel D162, Frame 1366-1425)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1910-1928 (Reel D163, Frame 1-14)
  - Mora, F. Luis, 1940, undated (Reel D163, Frame 15-20)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1930-1944, undated (Reel D163, Frame 21-36)
  - Myers, Jerome & Ethel, 1940, undated (Reel D163, Frame 37-44)
  - New Society of Artists, 1925-1926, undated (Reel D163, Frame 45-50)
  - New York School of Applied Design for Women, 1916-1940 (Reel D163, Frame 51-62)
  - Pen & Brush, 1916, undated (Reel D163, Frame 77-80)
  - Pennell, Joseph, 1915-1922 (Reel D163, Frame 81-99)
  - Perrine, Van Dearing, 1918, 1923, undated (Reel D163, Frame 100-106)
  - Preston, James, 1938, 1943, undated (Reel D163, Frame 107-112)
  - Pyle, Howard, 1907 (Reel D163, Frame 113)
  - Remington, Frederic, 1898, 1900, undated (Reel D163, Frame 114-122)
  - Roberts, W. Goodridge, 1929-1941, undated (Reel D163, Frame 123-145)
  - Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., Jr. (Abby), 1931, undated (Reel D163, Frame 146-148)
  - Roerich, Nicholas, 1921-1930 (Reel D163, Frame 149-178)
  - Roorbach, Eloise, 1912, 1920, 1924 (Reel D163, Frame 179-183)
  - Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, 1905 (Reel D163, Frame 184)
  - Shinn, Everett, 1908, 1911, 1953 (Reel D163, Frame 185-190)
  - Sloan, John, 1909-1952 (Reel D163, Frame 191-235)
  - Smith, Pamela C., 1907, undated (Reel D163, Frame 236-239)
  - Speicher, Eugene, circa 1925-1930 (Reel D163, Frame 240-245)
  - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1909, 1933, 1947 (Reel D163, Frame 246-254)
  - Sterner, Marie (Mrs. Albert), undated (Reel D163, Frame 255-258)
  - Taft, Lorado, 1906, 1908, 1915 (Reel D163, Frame 259-263)
  - Tarbell, Ida M., 1917 (Reel D163, Frame 264-268)
  - Thomas, Joseph B., 1925-1941, undated (Reel D163, Frame 269-277)
  - The Touchstone Magazine, 1917-1921 (Reel D163, Frame 278-288)
  - Troubetzkoy, Pierre & Amelie, 1902-1936, undated (Reel D163, Frame 289-333)
  - Ver Beck, W. Francis, 1933, undated (Reel D163, Frame 334-335)
  - Vonnoh, Robert W. & Bessie Potter, 1913, undated (Reel D163, Frame 336-339)
  - Walker, Horatio, 1919 (Reel D163, Frame 340)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1931-1939 (Reel D163, Frame 341-347)
  - Wiborg, Mary Hoyt, 1925-1927 (Reel D163, Frame 348-352)
  - Wildenstein & Co., 1927, 1939, undated (Reel D163, Frame 353-355)
  - Wright, Russel & Mary, undated (Reel D163, Frame 356-362)
  - Yeats, John Butler, 1915-1922, 1940-1941, undated (Reel D163, Frame 363-373)
  - Unidentified Letters, 1906-1945, undated (Reel D163, Frame 374-406)
- Dance and Theatre Correspondence/Subject Files, 1902-1953, undated, Series 5:; (Box 2-3; 0.8 linear feet)
  This series contains correspondence with actors, dancers, playwrights, theatre patrons, dance and theatre organizations and clubs, and individual theatres, as well as related materials collected by Roberts. Folders may contain a variety of material, including letters, invitations, photographs, programs and event booklets, news clippings, and other printed material.
  Roberts was friends with many prominent performers from the early twentieth century and a small amount of their correspondence is found here. She wrote and published articles about dancers, actors, and other performers, but was also a great admirer and supporter of modern dance and theatre, participating in many organizations, including the Drama League of America in which she was a member of their Playgoing Committee of New York. Correspondence of note is with actors Charles "Orlando" Coburn, William Faversham, and Walter Hampden, actresses Eva Le Gallienne and Mary Shaw, playwrights Louis K. Anspacher, Cosmo Hamilton, and Percy MacKaye, dancer and artist Angna Enters, theatre patron Mrs. Samuel "Minnie" Untermyer, and Romola Nijinsky, wife of dancer Vaslav Nijinsky. Additional significant correspondence is with the "Duncan Dancers", students of Isadora Duncan, including Anna, Irma, Lisa, and others. There is also a small amount of correspondence with Isadora Duncan and her brother Augustin Duncan and his wife Margherita, as well as printed material documenting their careers as dancers and photographs of Isadora and Anna Duncan. Other items of note in this series include photographs of actress Maxine Elliott and dancer Doris Humphrey, and a small painted self-portrait of Angna Enters. Several folders of Miscellaneous Dance Files include correspondence and a large amount of printed material about individual dancers and performances.
  - Actor-Managers, Inc., 1927-1931, undated (Reel D164, Frame 258-261)
  - Actors' Fund Matinee Club, 1930 (Reel D164, Frame 257)
  - American Laboratory Theatre, 1925-1930 (Reel D163, Frame 464-472)
  - Ames, Winthrop, 1910-1917 (Reel D163, Frame 473-478)
  - Anderson, John Murray, 1920-1925 (Reel D163, Frame 479-481)
  - Anspacher, Louis K. and Kathryn, 1916-1947 (Reel D163, Frame 482-496)
  - Baker, George P., 1913 (Reel D163, Frame 497)
  - Becque, Don Oscar & Elizabeth, 1945, undated (Reel D163, Frame 498-501)
  - Bernays, Edward L., 1915-1916, 1938 (Reel D163, Frame 502-508)
  - Bowers, Edward J., 1915-1917, 1946, undated (Reel D163, Frame 509-516)
  - Castle, Irene, 1918, 1922, 1950, undated (Reel D163, Frame 517-522)
  - Coburn, Charles (Orlando) & Ivah (1 of 2), 1909-1944, undated (Reel D163, Frame 523-557)
  - Coburn, Charles (Orlando) & Ivah (2 of 2), 1909-1944, undated (Reel D163, Frame 558-608)
  - Collier, Constance, undated (Reel D163, Frame 609)
  - The Country Playhouse, 1917 (Reel D164, Frame 301-303)
  - De Mille, Agnes & Anna G., 1935, 1942, undated (Reel D163, Frame 842-846)
  - Drama League of America (1 of 2), 1911-1919, undated (Reel D163, Frame 847-862)
  - Drama League of America (2 of 2), 1911-1919, undated (Reel D163, Frame 863-938)
  - Draper, Muriel, 1932-1941, undated (Reel D163, Frame 939-945)
  - Duncan, Augustin & Margherita, 1913-1943, undated (Reel D163, Frame 1053-1076)
  - Duncan Dancers (1 of 2), circa 1917-1950, undated (Reel D163, Frame 946-985)
  - Duncan Dancers (2 of 2), circa 1917-1950, undated (Reel D163, Frame 986-1052)
  - Duncan, Isadora, 1908-1949, undated, (2 folders) (Reel D163, Frame 1077-1178)
  - Elliott, Maxine, circa 1916-1920 (Reel D163, Frame 1179-1186)
  - Emery, Gilbert, circa 1922-1925 (Reel unfilmed)
  - Enters, Angna, 1926-1949, undated (Reel D163, Frame 1187-1226)
  - Episcopal Actor's Guild, 1947, 1953, undated (Reel D164, Frame 338-356)
  - Equity Players, Inc., 1924, undated (Reel D164, Frame 357-361)
  - Faversham, William & Julie, 1902-1927, undated (Reel D163, Frame 1227-1266)
  - Garden, Mary, undated (Reel D163, Frame 1267-1277)
  - Guy, Edna, 1934, undated (Reel D163, Frame 1278-1279)